Finding Aid for the Japanese American Research Project Collection about Japanese in the U.S. (Yuji Ichioka papers) LSC.2010.00
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Personal Papers
  - McGovern Papers, 1942-1945; 5.0 linear ft.
    - Various Incarceree Publications at Incarceration Camps, 0.5 linear ft.
      - Publication at the Poston Relocation Center, Arizona., 1943; (1 item) (Box 120, Folder 3)
        - American Red Cross, Colorado River Project, WRA, The First Year: Story of the Red Cross in Poston [Soritsu isshunen kinen] [characters]. Poston, Arizona., November 1943; (26pp., 8pp., mimeographed) (Box 120, Folder 3)
      - Publication at the Rohwer Relocation Center, Arkansas., 1943; (1 item) (Box 120, Folder 4)
        - Rohwer Outpost, Lil Dan'l: One Year in a Relocation Center. Rohwer, Arkansas., 1943; (28pp., mimeographed) (Box 120, Folder 4)
      - Publications at the Central Utah Relocation Center, Topaz, Utah., 1943-1944; (5 items) (Box 120, Folder 5)
        - Reports Division, Topaz Relocation Center, Facts You Should Know. Topaz, Utah., n.d. (ca. 1943); (8pp., mimeographed) (Box 120, Folder 5)
        - Project Reports Division, Historical Section, Central Utah Relocation Project, Welcome to Topaz. Topaz, Utah., January 1943; (30pp., mimeographed) (Box 120, Folder 5)
        - Trek, vol. I, no.2-3., February 1943; June 1943; (2 issues) (Box 120, Folder 5)
          A special publication of the Project Reports Division, Central Utah Relocation Center.
        - Historical Section, Project Reports Division, Central Utah Project, All Aboard. Topaz, Utah., Spring 1944; (54 pp.) (Box 120, Folder 5)
      - Publications at the Tule Lake Center, Newell, California., 1943-1944; (3 items) (Box 120, Folder 6)
        - Tulean Dispatch, Tule Lake Relocation Center. A Tule Lake Interlude: First Anniversary, May 27, 1942-1943. Newell, California: The Tulean Dispatch., (109pp., mimeographed) (Box 120, Folder 6)
        - Tulean Dispatch Magazine, vol. I, no.8., March 1943; (Mimeographed) (Box 120, Folder 6)
          A literary magazine.
        - WRA, Tule Lake Segregation Center, Information concerning Tule Lake Center. Newell, California., September 1944; (20pp., mimeographed) (Box 120, Folder 6)
      - The MISLS Album. n.p., n.d.; (136pp., 1 item) (Box 120, Folder 7)
        A photo album published by the Album Staff of the Military Intelligence Service Language School.
      - English pamphlets and leaflets on the wartime incarceration and resettlement of the Japanese, published by various civic and church organizations., 1942-1945; (21 items) (Box 120, Folder 8)
      - Neal Woodruff, editor, Estespeaks. Topeka, Kansas: Student Christian Movement of the Rocky Mountain Region., December 1944; (1 item, mimeographed, no pagination) (Box 120, Folder 9)
        A report of the Estes Student-Faculty Conference of the Student Christian Movement, Rocky Mountain Region, at Association Camp Colorado on June 22-July 1, 1944.
      - A collection of newsletters, leaflets, newspapers, and clippings of newspaper and magazine articles., 1942-1945; (43 items) (Box 120, Folder 10)
        Mostly on the wartime incarceration of the Japanese, incarceration camps, and other related topics.
  - Mementos of the Issei, ca. 1904-1947; 0.5 linear ft.
    - A notebook binder containing mementos of the Issei in Hawaii and continental United States., ca. 1904-1947; (1 book) (Box 163)
  - Mihara Papers, n.d.; 1 folder
    Mihara Tokinobu [characters] (1897- ). Newspaperman, Japanese language teacher and author, San Francisco. A native of Ehime Prefecture. Graduate, Waseda University, B.A., 1920. Arrived in 1920. Became blind while incarcerated at Heart Mountain. Devout Christian.
    - Guided by my white cane., n.d.; (Manuscript, 173pp., 1 item) (Box 160, Folder 16)
      An incomplete autobiography.
  - Mikuriya Papers, 1964-1965; 2 folders
    Mikuriya Tadafumi [characters] (1899- ). Civil Engineer, East Coast. A native of Saga Prefecture. Graduate, Kumamoto Engineering College. Arrived in America in 1923. Graduate, University of Pennsylvania, B.S., 1926, and M.S., 1927.
    - An autobiography., ca. 1965; (Manuscript, 50pp., 1 item) (Box 156, Folder 1)
    - Photocopies of business correspondence; and other miscellaneous papers., 1964-1965 and n.d.; (5 items) (Box 156, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Personal Papers, n.d.; 1.5 linear ft.
    Mostly incidental biographical materials and related papers of individuals.
    - Miscellaneous., (39 folders) (Box 161)
    - Miscellaneous., (35 folders) (Box 162)
    - Miscellaneous., (1 folder) (Box 163)
  - Miyagishima Papers, 1960; 1 folder
    Miyagishima Nonkib [characters]. Pseudonym. Biography unknown.
    - Sanchubu ni okeru Nihonjin no ashiato [characters] [A history of the Japanese in the Rocky Mountain region]., ca. 1960; (Manuscripts, 5 notebooks, approximately 100 pp.) (Box 160, Folder 17)
  - Morita Papers, 1942-1944; 1 folder
    Morita Jiro [characters] (1892- ). Merchant, Pasadena, California. A native of Shizuoka Prefecture who arrived in 1909.
    - Miscellaneous papers., 1942-1944; (21 items) (Box 159, Folder 4)
      regarding his incarceration at Poston and his service as a Japanese language instructor, United States Military Intelligence Service Language School, Camp Savage, Minnesota.
  - Murakami Papers, 1929-1941; 0.5 linear ft.
    Murakami Noboru [characters] (1889-1958). Businessman, Los Angeles. A native of Hiroshima Prefecture who arrived in 1907. Secretary, Japanese Hotel and Apartment Association of Southern California, before World War II.
    - Diaries and Correspondence, 0.5 linear ft. (9 diary books and correspondence)
      - Diaries., 1929, 1933-1938 and 1940-1941; (9 diary-books) (Box 130)
      - Letters received from relatives in Japan and other miscellaneous papers., ca. 1936-ca. 1941; (13 items) (Box 130)
  - Nicholson Papers, 1964; 1 folder
    Herbert V. Nicholson. Biography unknown.
    - Notes on evacuation of Japanese during World War II: Being personal experience of H.V. Nicholson., January 1964; (Manuscript, 29pp., 1 item) (Box 160, Folder 18)
  - Niimura Papers, 1922-1965; 1 folder
    Niimura Eiichi [characters]. Dancer-choreographer, New York City. A native of Nagano Prefecture who arrived in 1922. From 1932 he performed in the major theaters of America, Europe, Asia, and Africa. Director, 61, Ballet Arts School of Carnegie Hall. Popularly known as Yeichi Nimura.
    - Concert press releases, a chronological table of concert tours and productions from 1937-1965, and magazine articles about Niimura along with reviews of his performances., 1922-1965; (14 items) (Box 156, Folder 3)
  - Nishimura Papers, ca. 1919-1947; 0.5 linear ft.
    Nishimura Yoshio [characters] (1875-1947). Laborer, socialist, and newspaperman. A native of Nara Prefecture but raised in Hokkaid. Served in the Japanese Imperial Navy. Arrived in America around 1906. Editor, Kyoyu Jiji [characters] [the Kyoyu Times] and Rd no Chikara [characters] [The Workers' Power], newspapers printed for the Japanese laborers in the United States. Reporter for the Ofu Nippo [characters] [Sacramento Daily News] from 1939-1941. His pen name was Kantaishi [characters].
    - Katayama Sen letters. From Katayama Sen, Moscow, to Nishimura Yoshio, New York., ca. 1928-ca. 1931; (13 items) (Box 131, Folder 1)
      4 postcards and 7 letters. Includes 2 photographs of Katayama Sen.
    - Documents regarding the Japanese Socialist Movement in the United States., ca. 1919-1945 (Box 131, Folder 2)
      - Constitution of the Japanese Labor Fraternity., n.d.; (Manuscript, 3pp., 1 item) (Box 131, Folder 2)
      - Sangy rdkumiai rengkygikai no shsh [characters]. Printed by the Japanese Section of the Trade Union Educational League., (1p., 1 item) (Box 131, Folder 2)
        A leaflet announcing the opening of the International Trade Union League Conference to be held on August 30, 1929 in Cleveland, Ohio.
      - Wataru Kaji, We were seven: Report on Kwei-Nan Campaign. Chungking., 1945; (7pp. Mimeographed, 1 item) (Box 131, Folder 2)
      - Miscellany., (5 items) (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence of Nishimura regarding the labor movement in the United States., ca. 1919-ca. 1936; (11 items) (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence of Nishimura during World War II., April 1942-February 1946; (27 pieces) (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous personal correspondence of Nishimura. Postwar., (12 items) (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Diary, Nihonjin bochi nisshi [characters]., November 16, 1941-April 22, 1942; (1 notebook) (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - Clippings of newspaper articles written by Nishimura. Mostly unidentified., (?)-1947; (1 scrapbook) (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - 2 unidentified manuscripts, probably written by Nishimura., n.d. (Box 131, Folder 8)
      - Chapter II, on the China Incidents., (Manuscript, 13pp., 1 item) (Box 131, Folder 8)
      - Shinsei Nihon no shinzui o nigiri kseidh no shishin to seyo [characters] [Come to grips with the true objectives of New Japan and have the reformed Japanese move toward those directions]., (Manuscript, 9 pp.) (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - A collection of miscellaneous leaflets and magazine clippings., (8 items) (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Miscellany., (9 items) (Box 131, Folder 10)
  - Nishioka Papers, 1953-1961; 3 folders
    Nishioka Ryichi [characters] (1887- ). Sales clerk and bookkeeper, Southern California. A native of Hiroshima Prefecture who arrived in 1906. Graduate, University of California, Berkeley, M.S., Zoology, 1924?
    - A Koseki Tohon [Family Registry] of Nishioka Ryichi., March 7, 1961; (1 item) (Box 156, Folder 4)
    - Letters received from his relatives in Japan., 1957-1961; (39 letters) (Box 156, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence., 1953-1961; (8 items) (Box 156, Folder 6)
  - Obata Papers, ca. 1965; 1 folder, and Framed Sumie
    Obata Chiura [characters] (1884- ). Artist. Professor Emeritus of Art, University of California, Berkeley. A native of Iwate Prefecture who arrived in 1903.
    - Biographical sketches in English and Japanese and related papers., (4 items) (Box 156, Folder 7)
    - A large framed sumie: Glorious Struggle: Sequoia Gigantea in Storm., Sumie on silk, 36 x 22", n.d.; and a framed explanatory comment. (2 un-numbered oversize items)
      Also, a framed explanatory comment.
      NOTE: Item currently hangs in the Smith Room in the UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections.
  - Oi Papers, 1906-1966; 1.5 linear ft.
    Oi Matsunosuke [characters] (1885- ). Merchant and community leader, Southern California. A native of Kochi Prefecture who arrived in America in 1906. Active as an officer of various Japanese associations. Founding member of the postwar Japanese Chamber of Commerce of Southern California.
    - Biographical materials and Miscellaneous Materials, 1.5 linear ft.
      Includes papers, a scrapbook on World War II and incarceration, and documents on the postwar Japanese Chamber of Commerce of Southern California.
      - 3 manuscripts of Oi's autobiography. (Box 132, Folder 1)
        - Kuni o dete kara watakushi no ayunda ato, 1906-1966 [characters] [My life in the United States, 1906-1966]., (Manuscript, 56pp. Photocopy, 1 item) (Box 132, Folder 1)
        - Shussei yori chgakko sotsugy made: zempen [characters] [My childhood: Volume I] (incomplete)., n.d.; (Manuscript, 5pp., photocopy) (Box 132, Folder 1)
        - Watakushi no jigy nenbetsuhy [characters] [A chronological listing of my jobs and occupations in the United States, 1908-1960]., ca. 1960; (Manuscript, 7pp. Photocopy, 1 item) (Box 132, Folder 1)
      - Documents regarding Oi's wartime incarceration., 1942-1945; 1942-1944; (5 items) (Box 132, Folder 2)
        Includes correspondence regarding the alleged illegal seizure of Oi's properties by his Caucasian friends during his incarceration, 1942-1944; and a Japanese translation of the Geneva Convention, 1942-1945.
      - Documents regarding the Nanka Nikkeijin Kygikai [characters] [Japanese American Community Council of Los Angeles]., 1947-1948; (6 items) (Box 132, Folder 3)
        Includes a listing of the original members and the objectives of the organization.
      - Documents regarding the Nanka Nikkeijin Kai [characters] [Japanese Chamber of Commerce of Southern California]., 1950; (2 items) (Box 132, Folder 4)
        - Nanka Nikkeijin Kai Kaisoku [characters] [Bylaws]. (Box 132, Folder 4)
          Original and amended versions.
        - Kaih [characters] [Bulletin]., December 1, 1950; January 1, 1951 (Box 132, Folder 4)
          vol.II, no.12 (December 1, 1950)
          vol.III, no.1 (January 1, 1951)
      - Scattered issues of the Nanka Nissh Kaih [characters] [Japanese Chamber of Commerce of Southern California Bulletin], no.1-., December 12, 1948-October 15, 1949; (25 issues) (Box 132, Folder 5)
      - Kaikei Hokoku [characters] (financial reports) of the Japanese Chamber of Commerce of Southern California (Incomplete)., December 1952-October 1958; (30 reports) (Box 132, Folder 6)
      - Notices, announcements and miscellaneous reports of the Japanese Chamber of Commerce of Southern California., ca. 1950-1958; (32 pieces) (Box 132, Folder 7)
        Includes newspaper clippings on the organization.
      - Nanka Nikkeijin Kai Meibo [characters] [Directory, Japanese Chamber of Commerce of Southern California]. Los Angeles., September 1950; October 1, 1950; (Ditto, 10pp., 1 item) (Box 132, Folder 8)
        Appends the Nanka Nikkeijin Kai [Bulletin], vol. II, no.10.
      - Documents regarding the Rafu Seinan Nikkeijin Shiny Chochiku Kumiai [characters] [Los Angeles Southwest Japanese Credit Union]., ca. 1954-1956; May 1, 1956; (4 pieces) (Box 132, Folder 9)
        Includes a copy of the bylaws (Mimeographed) and Bulletin no. 55 (May 1, 1956).
      - Papers regarding the Shink Tshi Kabushiki Kaisha [characters] [Shink Investment Company, Inc.]., 1956-1958; (3 pieces) (Box 132, Folder 10)
      - Reports and other materials distributed by the Anti-discrimination Committee of the Japanese American Citizens League (JACL)., 1948-1949; (37 items, mimeographed) (Box 132, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous reports and other materials regarding the JACL., 1946-1960; (25 items) (Box 132, Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous materials. Postwar., (20 items) (Box 132, Folder 13)
      - A scrapbook containing newspaper clippings from local presses, from the outbreak of World War II to the forced removal from the West Coast., December 1941-April 1942; (1 oversize scrapbook) (Box 722)
  - Oka Papers, 1914-1957; 1.0 linear ft.
    Oka Shigeki [characters] (1878-1959). Mover, printer, newspaper publisher, socialist, and author. A native of Kochi Prefecture. Employed by the Yorozu Choho before arriving in America in 1902. Operated the Kinmon Press in San Francisco and published the Amerika Shimbun and Ofu Nippo [Sacramento Daily News]. Incarcerated at Heart Mountain but released to work for the United States government in India during World War II.
    - Diary, Sources and Manuscripts, 0.5 linear ft.
      For a projected biography of Abiko Kytar. Also, other miscellaneous manuscripts and personal papers.
      - A diary of Oka Shigeki., 1914; (1 diary-book) (Box 133, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence of Oka Shigeki and miscellaneous manuscripts written during his incarceration at Heart Mountain., ca. June-November 1942; (12 items) (Box 133, Folder 2)
      - Personal correspondence of Oka Shigeki., 1956; (17 items) (Box 133, Folder 3)
      - Sources and manuscripts for a projected biography of Abiko Kyutaro. (Box 133, Folder 4-5)
        - Manuscripts., (17 items) (Box 133, Folder 4)
          1. Forward by Oka Shigeki, in both English and Japanese. 1957. 2pp. + 3pp.
          2. A copy of a speech given by Abiko Kyutaro commemorating the 30th Anniversary of the Northern California Japanese Buddhist Church in 1930. In Japanese. 6pp.
          3. Akashi Junzo [characters] Abiko-shi no insho: Shashin kekkon kinshi jiken no kioku [characters] [An impression of Mr. Abiko Kyutaro: a memory on the prohibition on the passage of picture-brides to the United States]. Nikko, 1956. In Japanese. 27pp.
          4. Konno Toyoji [characters] Senken no meiarishi kaitakusha Abiko Kyutaro-shi o keibo [characters] [A tribute to the enlightened pioneer, Abiko Kyutaro], Livingston, 1955. In Japanese. 6pp.
          5. Kodaira Kunio [characters] Chjitsu-naru kykaijin [characters] [A devoted Christian], Tokyo, 1956. In Japanese. 2pp.
          6. Kuroishi Kiyosaku [characters] Abiko Kyutaro o [characters] [Abiko Kyutaro], Sao Paulo, Brazil, n.d. In Japanese. Kuroishi is publisher of the Burajiru Jiho, a Japanese language newspaper published in Sao Paulo, Brazil. 36pp. + 4pp.
          7. Nakamura Kaju [characters] Abiko Kyutaro o [characters] [Abiko Kyutaro], Tokyo, 1956. In Japanese. 5pp.
          8. Kazuo Kay Nishida, Kyutaro Abiko: Pioneer with a Vision, n.d. In English. 2pp.
          9. Okina Hisamitsu [characters] Abiko Kyutaro o to watakushi [characters] [Abiko Kyutaro and I], Tokyo, [1956]. In Japanese. 31pp.
          10. Okubo Itsuji [characters] Ko Abiko Kyutaro shi no koseki o shinobite [characters] [Abiko Kyutaro and his accomplishments], Los Angeles, 1957. In Japanese. 2pp.
          11. Yamamura Shiro [characters] Abiko Kyutaro-kun o tsuiokushite [characters] [Reminiscence of Mr. Kyutaro Abiko], 1956. In both Japanese and English. 8pp. + 5pp.
          12. Yamano Masataro [characters] Sempai Abiko-san [characters] [Mr. Abiko: My esteemed senior], Tokyo, [1956]. In both Japanese and English. 8pp. + 6pp.
        - Correspondence Oka Shigeki received regarding the projected publication of Abiko's biography, mostly from acquaintances of Abiko living in Japan., 1956; (16 items) (Box 133, Folder 5)
      - Manuscripts of Oka Shigeki's articles., n.d.; (18 items) (Box 133, Folder 6)
        - Beikoku shgy kankdan to Koike Sryji [characters]., (2 pp.) (Box 133, Folder 6)
        - Beika Jgoman-yo-doru (hka yonsen-nihyaku-man-en ij) o Nihon nogyoseinen no tame jisan [characters]. (Box 133, Folder 6)
        - Tga-kun ni atau [characters]., (6 pp.) (Box 133, Folder 6)
        - Shoki tobei no josei tachi [characters]., (4pp., photocopy) (Box 133, Folder 6)
        - 'Yorozu Chh' jidai no Yamagata sensei: rokuj-nen mo mukashi no koto [characters]., (6pp., photocopy) (Box 133, Folder 6)
        - Kekkyoku shihonka wa awarena matsuro o tadoraneba naranai no de wa nai ka? [characters]., (4pp., photocopy) (Box 133, Folder 6)
        - Kaikoku isshi: Amerika Hikozo jijoden [characters], [I] & III., (13pp. + 3pp., photocopies) (Box 133, Folder 6)
        - Untitled (Autobiography)., (8pp., photocopy) (Box 133, Folder 6)
        - Kawariyuku Nihon-machi: Sk no koto desu [characters]., (25pp., photocopy) (Box 133, Folder 6)
        - Soko Kokusai Kyokai, Nichibei Kazoku Kurabu hokoku [characters]., (23pp., photocopy) (Box 133, Folder 6)
        - 8 other miscellaneous manuscripts. (Box 133, Folder 6)
      - Sources and documents collected by Oka Shigeki for his writing of articles., ca. 1933-ca. 1948; (14 items) (Box 133, Folder 7)
      - Taisho jnendo Rafu Nihonjinkai ykensha meibo [characters] [Roster of electors: Japanese Association of Los Angeles]., 1921; (4 pp.) (Box 133, Folder 8)
      - Ktoku Shusui [characters] Shutsugoku gin nijugoin (sekishokuki) [characters]., 1905; (1p., 1 item) (Box 133, Folder 9)
        A Chinese poem composed in a prison.
      - Miscellaneous published materials collected by Oka Shigeki. Mostly postwar., (14 items) (Box 133, Folder 10)
    - Newspapers, Clippings and Other Published Materials, 0.5 linear ft.
      - Amerika Shimbun [characters] [The America Shimbun], vol. III, no.1-2., May 29, 1957; November 12, 1958; (2 items) (Box 134, Folder 1)
        A weekly Japanese language newspaper published by Oka Shigeki in San Francisco.
      - Shmaky [characters] [Magic Mirror], no.1-2., n.d. (ca. 1926); (2 items) (Box 134, Folder 2)
        An exposé newspaper published by Osawa Eizo with Ikeda Toyohiko as editor in San Francisco.
      - Kujku Shinshi [characters], no.1., June 15, 1917; (1 item) (Box 134, Folder 3)
        A newspaper printed by Oka Shigeki in San Francisco mainly as an organ of zaibei Tosajin (people from the Province of Tosa).
      - Hakugekih [characters] [Mortar], no.2., November 11, 1939; (1 item) (Box 134, Folder 4)
        A newspaper printed in San Francisco with intent of challenging the established authorities in the Japanese community.
      - Shh Mitsuhoshi [characters] [The Three Star Weekly], vol. I, no.3., October 19, 1939; (1 item) (Box 134, Folder 5)
        A weekly printed in Los Angeles.
      - Clippings of Washizu Shakuma [characters] Rekishi emmetsu no nageki [characters], no.1-97 (complete)., ca. 1923; (1 scrapbook) (Box 134, Folder 6)
        A series of newspaper articles which appeared on the Nichibei Shimbun. Includes a few other newspaper clippings.
      - Clippings of newspaper articles written by Suzuki Mugen and published in the Ofu Nippo., (4 items) (Box 134, Folder 7)
        - "Ofu heigen doho kaikoshi" [characters] (An introductory article). (Box 134, Folder 7)
        - "Ofu heigen doho no hatten shiki" [characters], 1-4. (Box 134, Folder 7)
        - "Doho yo kakuji no rekishi ni mezamete chusho hibo o haiseyo" [characters], 1-4. (Box 134, Folder 7)
        - "Shoki no tobeisha" [characters], 1-3. (Box 134, Folder 7)
        - "Nihon minzoku to kaigai shiso" [characters], 1-5. (Box 134, Folder 7)
        - "Sakuramento heigen" [characters], 1-44. (Box 134, Folder 7)
        - "Sakuramento-gun" [characters], 1-9. (Box 134, Folder 7)
        - "Sakuramento-shi" [characters], 1-52. (Box 134, Folder 7)
      - Seid [characters]. Osaka, Japan., October 1, 1921; December 1938; April, October; December 1939; May-June, August-November-December 1940; January-February, July 1941; (15 items) (Box 134, Folder 8)
        A religious monthly magazine.
        vol.4, no.11 (October 1, 1921)
        vol.22, no.1 (December 1938), no.5 (April 1939) and no. 11 (October 1939)
        vol.23, no.1 (December 1939), no.6-7 (May-June 1940), and nos. 9-12 (August-November 1940)
        vol.24, no.1-3 (December 1940 and January-February 1941) and no. 8 (July 1941).
      - Assorted newspapers and magazines printed in America and Japan. Mostly postwar., (18 items) (Box 134, Folder 9)
    - Ken Yamada, The Vicissitudious Fifty Years of Life in America of Mr. Shinichiro Oka., n.d.; (Manuscript, 22pp., 1 item) (Box 159, Folder 5)
  - Onishi Papers, [ca.1945- ]; 1 folder
    Onishi Jitsuji [characters]. A farmer in Texas.
    - Thanking letters from relatives and friends in Japan for postwar care-packages which Onishi sent to them after World War II., (52 items) (Box 156, Folder 8)
  - Ono Papers, 1970; 1 folder
    Takayoshi Ono. Biography unknown.
    - Matsuri (film script)., (Photocopy, 13pp., 1 item) (Box 160, Folder 19)
  - Packard Papers, ca. 1921-1962; 1 folder
    Everett T. Packard (1867-1968). A native of Charlemont, Massachusetts and a longtime resident of Fox Island near Tacoma, Washington. Established friendly relations with the Japanese of Tacoma and Seattle.
    - Newspaper clippings, photos, correspondence, and other papers., ca. 1921-1962; (14 items) (Box 159, Folder 6)
  - Passports and Passage Permits, 1893-1924; 0.5 linear ft.
    - Notebook binder., 1893-1924; (15 passports and 4 permits in 1 book) (Box 163)
      Contains the Japanese government passports granted between 1893 and 1924 and toko kyokasho [characters] [Passage permit] issued between 1899 and 1920.
  - Rademaker Papers, 1936; 1.0 linear ft.
    John Adrian Rademaker. Professor of Sociology.
    - Statistical Data, 1936; 0.5 linear ft.